MARCO ESTRELLA

Mobile Software Engineer
Holder of Working holiday visa intending to
obtain a Sponsorship visa

mestrella.1991@gmail.com +61 435 720 050 Sydney, Australia English(Professional), Spanish(Native)

Seasoned Peruvian software engineer with 8 years in the industry developing applications for **Android** and **iOS** platforms and also **Back Ends**, ranging from enterprise to social Apps. I began working on a full time job as a professional at aged 19 and have since then developed large scale enterprise backend for telecom, apps for retail, banks and multinational companies. Currently, at age 27 I'm looking for a small or medium sized company where I can demonstrate and improve my skills on Android, iOS or both.

#### **SKILLS**

I invite you to look my Linkedin and Github profile.

Android Platform: Clean Architecture, MVVM, MVP, Kotlin, Java, C, C++, JNI, Androidx, Livecycle, Room, GreenDAO, Koin, Dagger2, Coroutines, RxJava, EventBus, Firebase, Google Maps v2, Google Location, Fabric, Material design and UI libraries, Socket.io, okHttp, Retrofit, Gson, Moshi, Fresco, Piccaso, Gidle, Timber, JUnit 4, Mockito, Roboelectric, Espresso.

**iOS Platform**: MVC, MVVM, **Swift 5, SwiftUI, Combine Framework, Swift 4**, RxSwift, Socket.io, Alamofire, **Codable**, UIKit, CoreData, **SQLite.swift**, Dispatch, **Swift Package Manager**, **Carthage**, Cocodapods, Firebase, MessageKit, Kingfisher.

**Backend**: Swift 4, Vapor 3, Java, Spring, Hibernate, EJB, Tomcat, Glassfish, Wildfly, Weblogic, MySQL, MS SQL, Oracle and etc.

Linux Platform: Swift 4 and 5, Swift package Manager, Gnome GTK+ 3.

Other Platforms: Arm 64, Raspberry Pi and Odroid.

#### **QUALIFICATIONS**

2017 | **Associate Android Developer**Google Developers <u>see credential</u>

2016 | **General English**University of Sydney – CET <u>see evidence</u>

2015 | Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 6 Programmer Oracle see credencial

2008 – 2013 | **Bachelor of Systems and informatics Engineering**Norbert Wiener University <u>see evidence</u>

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

July 2019 - Present | **Mobile Developer | Chasky |** Peru, Lima | Remote Job Working on a social network Android and iOS App.

March 2018 - Jun 2019 | **Swift Developer | Racepoint Energy |** USA, Mass | Remote Job Developed open source swift libraries for making android apps using Swift. It helped to reuse functional Swift libraries on Android. Also, worked on a Linux Swift App which run on ARM.

March 2017 - February 2018 | **Senior Android Software Engineer** | **Solera Mobile** | Peru Developed new Apps for company customers, maintaining and Refactoring the old ones. I also lead the standardisation of an architecture for making new Apps and I implemented tools for a better communication and working between the teams.

April 2015 - July 2016 | **Android Software Engineer** | **SYSCO AS** | Norway | Remote Job Maintained 7 existing android apps where I implemented modularization because those apps had many similar functions.

February 2014 - October 2014 | **Analyst & Programmer SOA** | **COSAPI DATA** | Peru Worked on the team which implemented Local Number Portability for one of the biggest telecom companies in Peru. I read/analysed the documents of the peruvian Government entity and created a process diagram. Then, we started to create the SOAP web services.

June 2013 - February 2014 | **Leader Web & Mobile Developer** | **Tecla Labs** | Peru Develop REST Apis for the Mobile Apps and help on the mobile development.

If you are interested in seeing more of my experience, let me invite you to see my <u>linkedin</u>, you also will be able to see my skill marks and recommendations.

# SOME APPS WHERE I WORKED



## Interbank APP 1.000.000+ Downloads

This is the <u>Interbank</u>'s banking app where users can see their accounts and transactions, send money, see and ask loans and much more.



# Oh! 500.000+ Downloads

Oh is a <a href="Intercorp">Intercorp</a>'s <a href="company">company</a>, this corporation also has a clothing store company and supermarkets where the customers can use the credit card and get discounts. This app allows the customer to manage the credit card.



### Clinica Internacional 100.000+ Downloads

This app helps the <u>clinic</u>'s patients to make and pay appointments, check the availability of the doctors, find the near clinic and also have a video call with a doctor if the patient want it.



#### Diariamente Ali 100.000+ Downloads

This app is a forum where women and moms can share their recipes, cleaning tips and ideas. <u>Alicorp</u> is a company which sells goodies, edible products and stuffs for home. The idea is to make buy some Alicorp's products by Articles.



# San Pablo 50.000+ Downloads

This app helps the San Pablo Clinic's patients to make appointments.



#### VIVE BCP 10.000+ Downloads

This app helps the employees of <u>BCP bank</u> to find their benefits such as discount in restaurants, hotels, shopping center, etc. They also can ask best interest loans, day offs or vacations for a month on the App.



# Chasky 5.000+ Downloads

This is a social network app which allow the users to chat, add contacts by phone numbers, share stories and see nightclubs' events. It's still being developed. The design is simple as the client wanted.



# Soat Protecta Security 1.000+ Downloads

Protecta is a insurance company which offers this App to its customer for contacting a crane assistance, mechanical help and so on.



# Vigilo Optimal 100+ Downloads

It is a <u>norwegian communication tool</u> for schools where teachers can register their and students' absences. This app is a complement of a web system.

I also maintain this apps.

# Mobile Software Engineer Holder of Working holiday visa intending to obtain a Sponsorship visa

mestrella.1991@gmail.com +61 435 720 050 Sydney, Australia English(Professional), Spanish(Native)



# **Teens Protecta Security 100+ Downloads**

Protecta is a insurance company which offers this App to students to know about its services and benefits.



# GoGas 100+ Downloads

The Repsol gas station offer this App to its customers to manage their cards for buying gas, get discounts and more benefits.



# PAD Alumni 100+ Downloads

The University of Piura in Peru offers this App to the students and attendees of the events and conferences they schedule. The user can see the events, check the information of the expositors, share their user info to other ones by a QR code and so on.

# **REFERENCES**

References will happily be supplied upon request.